<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Julio Cesar Eiras Melanda</title><link href="https://jcemelanda.github.io/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://jcemelanda.github.io/feeds/all.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://jcemelanda.github.io/</id><updated>2021-07-31T06:00:00+02:00</updated><entry><title>Pyhon, my favorite programming language</title><link href="https://jcemelanda.github.io/python-favorite.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2021-07-31T06:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2021-07-31T06:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Julio Melanda</name></author><id>tag:jcemelanda.github.io,2021-07-31:/python-favorite.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A few ideas and thoughts on why Python is my favorite&amp;nbsp;language&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Probably anyone that knows me knows I like Python, it&amp;#8217;s not really something new, as I have thousands of t-shirts from Python events I&amp;#8217;ve been all over Brazil from 2015 to&amp;nbsp;2019.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, I decided to try to put in words why I like it so much and it&amp;#8217;s so important in my life and my&amp;nbsp;career.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Simplicity&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think one of the first things that come to someone&amp;#8217;s mind when they think of Python is how simple it is. Python syntax is so straightforward that many times reading the code feels like reading&amp;nbsp;English.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Take this for&amp;nbsp;example:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;numbers&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="p"&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="mi"&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="mi"&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="mi"&gt;3&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;]&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class="k"&gt;for&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;number&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="ow"&gt;in&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;numbers&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="k"&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;number&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="mi"&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class="nb"&gt;print&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;number&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#8217;s just&amp;nbsp;beautiful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Rich options of 3rd party&amp;nbsp;libraries&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#8217;s common to see jokes that in python you can do whatever you want by just importing a&amp;nbsp;library.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#8217;s surely not as easy, but definitely you have a huge number of libraries that already do or helps you doing almost everything you want&amp;nbsp;to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some of the most amazing libraries I have used&amp;nbsp;are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;requests&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A library that makes it super easy and readable to call URLs using regular &lt;span class="caps"&gt;HTTP&lt;/span&gt; verbs like &lt;span class="caps"&gt;GET&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class="caps"&gt;POST&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class="caps"&gt;PUT&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class="caps"&gt;PATCH&lt;/span&gt; and &lt;span class="caps"&gt;DELETE&lt;/span&gt;. Here are some ecamples of how to call&amp;nbsp;it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;requests&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;get&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;test.com&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="n"&gt;requests&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;post&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;test.com&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;data&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;django&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Django is a full featured web framework that allows you to create web applications with an inspiration in the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;MVC&lt;/span&gt; (Model-View-Controller) application architecture, (&lt;span class="caps"&gt;MVT&lt;/span&gt; in Django - Models, Views and templates). It has a great &lt;span class="caps"&gt;ORM&lt;/span&gt; that lets you create and control relational databases and their tables using Python classes for Models. Besides that it allows you to query the data using the model instances in a really simple way. It&amp;#8217;s really easy and&amp;nbsp;powerful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not to mention that Django has an extensible admin interface that uses this same model classes to allow &lt;span class="caps"&gt;CRUD&lt;/span&gt; operations and the management of the data in your&amp;nbsp;application.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A simple example of the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;ORM&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class="c1"&gt;# Given a model User you can filter the users by a given name like&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="n"&gt;User&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;objects&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;filter&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;Mark&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;pygame&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pygame is a simple &lt;span class="caps"&gt;SDL&lt;/span&gt; game engine. You need to control basically everything, even the flow of the game loop, but that doesn&amp;#8217;t make it a bad engine, actually that makes you understand in a much deeper level how a game works, the control of printing the images on the screen, the sprites animation and even&amp;nbsp;collision.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Surely, Pygame lets you use some libraries for physics and 3D (OpenGL) for example. I myself wrote a small library to help control the camera and make it follow an object&amp;nbsp;smoothly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#8217;d be too long to put pygame code here, but I&amp;#8217;ll leave a link to a github repo containing a game I&amp;nbsp;wrote.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/jcemelanda/MathShooter"&gt;Math&amp;nbsp;Shooter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Powerful standard&amp;nbsp;library&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You may be asking yourself why should I want to make a language more complex bringing so many functionalities into the standard library if we can have tons of libraries that do those things just a &lt;code&gt;import&lt;/code&gt; command away from&amp;nbsp;you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The thing is, managing dependencies can get quite complicated and the standard library have a high degree of optimization as most of it is written in C and works with the Python &lt;span class="caps"&gt;VM&lt;/span&gt; in a lower level than most libraries. That makes it faster in many cases and more&amp;nbsp;efficient.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some of my favorite libraries in the standard library are &lt;code&gt;random&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;itertools&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;regex&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;statistics&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;functools&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;pickle&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The zen of&amp;nbsp;Python&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you open a python shell and execute &lt;code&gt;import this&lt;/code&gt; you&amp;#8217;ll see a poem that kind of summarizes the philosophy behind&amp;nbsp;Python.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
The Zen of Python, by Tim Peters

Beautiful is better than ugly.
Explicit is better than implicit.
Simple is better than complex.
Complex is better than complicated.
Flat is better than nested.
Sparse is better than dense.
Readability counts.
Special cases aren't special enough to break the rules.
Although practicality beats purity.
Errors should never pass silently.
Unless explicitly silenced.
In the face of ambiguity, refuse the temptation to guess.
There should be one-- and preferably only one --obvious way to do it.
Although that way may not be obvious at first unless you're Dutch.
Now is better than never.
Although never is often better than *right* now.
If the implementation is hard to explain, it's a bad idea.
If the implementation is easy to explain, it may be a good idea.
Namespaces are one honking great idea -- let's do more of those!
&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just read it and you&amp;#8217;ll see how those verses can inspire you to write better&amp;nbsp;code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The Python&amp;nbsp;Community&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I met the language in 2007 and fell in love with it, but was in 2015, when I went to my first Python conference that I found out Python is not just a technology. It&amp;#8217;s a community of people that love to share knowledge and that try to make the world a better&amp;nbsp;place. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I met some of the best developers I ever dreamed of meeting like David Beazley and Luciano Ramalho and after the conference we&amp;#8217;d go all together to a bar and talk until very late at&amp;nbsp;night.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I learned so much and I was able to teach and help to. I got involved with PyLadies and DjangoGirls initiatives and I could inspire people and get inspired by them&amp;nbsp;also.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Finally&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Those are just some brief reasons I have Python as my preferred language and I try to apply it everywhere I find it&amp;nbsp;useful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope this can inspire you as much as I got inspired myself all this&amp;nbsp;years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Happy coding and please tell me what you think in the&amp;nbsp;comments!&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Opinion"></category><category term="python"></category><category term="preferences"></category><category term="stack"></category></entry><entry><title>Pyhon, minha linguagem de programação preferida</title><link href="https://jcemelanda.github.io/python-favorite-pt_BR.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2021-07-31T06:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2021-07-31T06:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Julio Melanda</name></author><id>tag:jcemelanda.github.io,2021-07-31:/python-favorite-pt_BR.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Algumas idéias e pensamentos sobre por que Python é minha linguagem&amp;nbsp;favorita&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Provavelmente quem me conhece sabe que gosto de Python, não é realmente algo novo, pois tenho milhares de camisetas de eventos Python que estive em todo o Brasil de 2015 a&amp;nbsp;2019.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Então, decidi tentar colocar em palavras porque eu gosto tanto desta linguagem e porque é tão importante na minha vida e na minha&amp;nbsp;carreira.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Simplicidade&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Acho que uma das primeiras coisas que vêm à mente de alguém quando pensa em Python é como ele é simples. A sintaxe do Python é tão direta que, muitas vezes, ler o código é como ler em&amp;nbsp;inglês.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Veja por&amp;nbsp;exemplo:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;numbers&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="p"&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="mi"&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="mi"&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="mi"&gt;3&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;]&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class="k"&gt;for&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;number&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="ow"&gt;in&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;numbers&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="k"&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;number&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="mi"&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class="nb"&gt;print&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;number&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;É&amp;nbsp;lindo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Muitas opções de bibliotecas de&amp;nbsp;terceiros&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;É comum ver piadas que em python você pode fazer o que quiser apenas importando uma&amp;nbsp;biblioteca.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Certamente não é tão fácil, mas definitivamente você tem um grande número de bibliotecas que já fazem ou ajudam você a fazer quase tudo o que você&amp;nbsp;deseja.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Algumas das bibliotecas mais incríveis que usei&amp;nbsp;são:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;requests&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Uma biblioteca que torna muito fácil e legível chamar URLs usando verbos &lt;span class="caps"&gt;HTTP&lt;/span&gt; regulares como &lt;span class="caps"&gt;GET&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class="caps"&gt;POST&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class="caps"&gt;PUT&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class="caps"&gt;PATCH&lt;/span&gt; e &lt;span class="caps"&gt;DELETE&lt;/span&gt;. Aqui estão alguns exemplos de como&amp;nbsp;usá-la.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;requests&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;get&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;test.com&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="n"&gt;requests&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;post&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;test.com&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;data&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;django&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Django é um framework web completo que permite criar aplicações web com inspiração na arquitetura de aplicação &lt;span class="caps"&gt;MVC&lt;/span&gt; (Model-View-Controller), (&lt;span class="caps"&gt;MVT&lt;/span&gt; em Django - Models, Views e templates). Possui um ótimo &lt;span class="caps"&gt;ORM&lt;/span&gt; que permite criar e controlar bancos de dados relacionais e suas tabelas usando classes Python para modelos. Além disso, permite consultar os dados usando as instâncias do modelo de uma forma muito simples. É muito fácil e&amp;nbsp;poderoso.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sem mencionar que o Django tem uma interface de administração extensível que usa essas mesmas classes de modelo para permitir operações &lt;span class="caps"&gt;CRUD&lt;/span&gt; e o gerenciamento dos dados em sua&amp;nbsp;aplicação.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Um exemplo simples de uso do &lt;span class="caps"&gt;ORM&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class="c1"&gt;# Given a model User you can filter the users by a given name like&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="n"&gt;User&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;objects&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;filter&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;Mark&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;pygame&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pygame é uma game engine &lt;span class="caps"&gt;SDL&lt;/span&gt; simples. Você precisa controlar basicamente tudo, até mesmo o fluxo do loop do jogo, mas isso não o torna uma engine ruim, na verdade faz você entender em um nível muito mais profundo como um jogo funciona, o controle de mostrar as imagens na tela , a animação dos sprites e até mesmo a&amp;nbsp;colisão.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Certamente, Pygame permite que você use algumas bibliotecas para física e 3D (OpenGL), por exemplo. Eu mesmo escrevi uma pequena biblioteca para ajudar a controlar a câmera e fazê-la seguir um objeto&amp;nbsp;suavemente.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Seria muito longo colocar um exemplo de código do pygame aqui, mas deixarei um link para um repositório github contendo um jogo que&amp;nbsp;escrevi.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/jcemelanda/MathShooter"&gt;Math&amp;nbsp;Shooter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Bibliotecas Padrão&amp;nbsp;Poderosas&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Você pode estar se perguntando por que eu deveria querer fazer uma linguagem mais complexa trazendo tantas funcionalidades para a biblioteca padrão se podemos ter toneladas de bibliotecas que fazem essas coisas apenas um comando &lt;code&gt;import&lt;/code&gt; longe de&amp;nbsp;você.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O fato é que gerenciar dependências pode ficar bem complicado e a biblioteca padrão tem um alto grau de otimização, já que a maior parte dela é escrita em C e trabalha com a &lt;span class="caps"&gt;VM&lt;/span&gt; Python em um nível mais baixo do que a maioria das bibliotecas. Isso o torna mais rápido e eficiente em muitos&amp;nbsp;casos.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Algumas das minhas bibliotecas favoritas na biblioteca padrão são &lt;code&gt;random&lt;/code&gt;,&lt;code&gt;itertools&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;regex&lt;/code&gt;,&lt;code&gt;statistics&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;functools&lt;/code&gt; e&lt;code&gt;pickle&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;O &amp;#8220;Zen&amp;#8221; do&amp;nbsp;Python&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Se você abrir um shell python e executar &lt;code&gt;import this&lt;/code&gt;, verá um poema que meio que resume a filosofia por trás do&amp;nbsp;Python.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
O Zen do Python, por Tim Peters, tradução livre

Belo é melhor do que feio.
Explícito é melhor do que implícito.
Simples é melhor que complexo.
Complexo é melhor do que complicado.
Plano é melhor do que aninhado.
O esparso é melhor do que o denso.
A legibilidade conta.
Casos especiais não são especiais o suficiente para quebrar as regras.
Embora a praticidade supere a pureza.
Os erros nunca devem passar silenciosamente.
A menos que seja explicitamente silenciado.
Diante da ambigüidade, recuse a tentação de adivinhar.
Deve haver uma - e de preferência apenas uma - maneira óbvia de fazer as coisas.
Embora esse caminho possa não ser óbvio no início, a menos que você seja holandês.
Agora é melhor do que nunca.
Embora nunca seja sempre melhor do que * agora *.
Se a implementação for difícil de explicar, é uma má ideia.
Se a implementação for fácil de explicar, pode ser uma boa ideia.
Os namespaces são uma ótima ideia - vamos fazer mais disso!
&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Basta lê-lo e você verá como esses versos podem inspirá-lo a escrever um código&amp;nbsp;melhor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;A Comunidade&amp;nbsp;Python&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Conheci a linguagem em 2007 e me apaixonei por ela, mas foi em 2015, quando fui à minha primeira conferência Python, que descobri que Python não é apenas uma tecnologia. É uma comunidade de pessoas que ama compartilhar conhecimento e tenta fazer do mundo um lugar&amp;nbsp;melhor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Conheci alguns dos melhores desenvolvedores que já sonhei em conhecer, como David Beazley e Luciano Ramalho e depois da conferência íamos todos juntos a um bar e conversávamos até tarde da&amp;nbsp;noite.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eu aprendi muito e pude ensinar e ajudar. Eu me envolvi com as iniciativas PyLadies e DjangoGirls e pude inspirar as pessoas e ser inspirado por elas&amp;nbsp;também.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Finalmente&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Esses são apenas alguns breves motivos pelos quais tenho Python como minha linguagem preferida e tentaro aplicá-lo em todos os lugares que considero&amp;nbsp;útil.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Espero que isso possa inspirar você tanto quanto eu me inspirei todos esses&amp;nbsp;anos.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Boa programação e por favor me diga o que você achou nos&amp;nbsp;comentários!&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Opinion"></category><category term="python"></category><category term="preferences"></category><category term="stack"></category></entry><entry><title>Hello World</title><link href="https://jcemelanda.github.io/hello-world.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2021-07-30T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2021-07-30T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Julio Melanda</name></author><id>tag:jcemelanda.github.io,2021-07-30:/hello-world.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Hello, this is my first post here in this&amp;nbsp;blog.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Hi!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#8217;s been a really long time since I wrote a blog post and it&amp;#8217;s actually quite harder then I expected to get back to&amp;nbsp;it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this blog you should expect me to talk about technology. Whatever I find relevant in what I&amp;#8217;m studying, as I love to teach, I&amp;#8217;ll post some tutorials&amp;nbsp;also.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope you will enjoy the content and feel free to contact me in the comments&amp;nbsp;:D&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="General"></category><category term="hello"></category><category term="start"></category></entry><entry><title>Olá Mundo</title><link href="https://jcemelanda.github.io/hello-world-pt_BR.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2021-07-30T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2021-07-30T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Julio Melanda</name></author><id>tag:jcemelanda.github.io,2021-07-30:/hello-world-pt_BR.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Olá, este é meu primeiro post aqui neste&amp;nbsp;blog.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Olá!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Faz muito tempo desde a última vez que  escrevi um post num blog, e está sendo bem mais complicado do que eu esperava para&amp;nbsp;retomar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Neste blog, você pode esperar que eu fale de tecnologia. Qualquer coisa que eu ache relevante que eu esteja estudando, como eu adoro ensinar, vou postar tutoriais&amp;nbsp;também.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Espero que goste do conteúdo e fique à contade para interagir nos comentários&amp;nbsp;:D&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="General"></category><category term="hello"></category><category term="start"></category></entry></feed>